

Tiago Carreira DevOps Engineer

- Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
- © +55 21 98303-3680
- tiago.g.carreira@gmail.com
- inkedin.com/in/tcarreira
- github.com/tcarreira

Soft Skills

- Productivity passionate
- Fast learner
- Highly adaptable
- Proactive and autonomous
- Good communicator
- Friendly and team player

Technical Skills



























Python

Monitoring

REST

Technological Values







Everything as code



Community

Personal Interests







Podcasts. Audiobooks

Activeness, Achievement

Learning, Improving

Languages

Portuguese



English



Spanish



French

0000

Having 10+ years of experience with DevOps, I'm experienced with modern technologies (eg: Docker), proficient with Linux systems and many DevOps tools (Kubernetes, CI/CD, IaC) and I'm a Python and Go developer.

Passionate about Linux, Open Source and productivity (I love scripting and automation). No person should be a single point of failure - procedures should be documented and/or automated.

I'm looking towards working with **smart people**, with whom I could learn and help learning; where **autonomy** is a valuable asset and improving is more important than finding who made a mistake.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps / Cloud Specialist @ Globo.com

DevOps / Cloud Specialist - August 2020 - Present (2+ years) Prio de Janeiro, Brazil

- Maintaining an Open Source PaaS (Platform as a Service) in Go tsuru.io | github.com/tsuru
- Managing multiple Kubernetes Clusters (with custom resources) 300+ nodes | 15k+ pods
- Infrastructure deployment and automation at GCP with terraform
- Core developer on Open Source Software (backend, cli, terraform providers mainly Go)

DevOps/Operations Engineer @ SAPO (BOLD by devoteam)

July 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 6 months) PLisbon, Portugal

- Implemented a monitoring stack with High Availability, using Grafana + Prometheus + Thanos
- Developed a Python/Django RESTful API for SSL Cert management (from scratch to production)
- DevOps advocate: improving Continuous Integration and best practices among the organization
- Data Center migration: bare metal, VM's, networking, data and storage (ensuring no downtime)
- Maintaining 500+ servers (using Puppet), 100+ services, both legacy and modern systems, on-call 24/7

DevOps Engineer @ Premium Minds

December 2013 - June 2017 (3 years 7 months) PLisbon, Portugal

- Migrated on-premises infrastructure to AWS (EC2, RDS, VPC, ...)
- Infrastructure as code with python/boto3
- Defined the infrastructure and deployment pipeline for a High Available service on AWS telpark.com
- Managing Continuous Integration using Jenkins and Puppet

EDUCATION

Certifications

- August 2022 CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator @ The Linux Foundation
- September 2021 GCP: Associate Cloud Engineer @ Google Cloud Certified

Training & Courses

- June 2022 CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator @ A Cloud Guru
- July 2021 Cloud Engineer @ Pluralsight
- May 2020 NDG Linux I/II course @ Cisco Networking Academy
- Jan 2019 LPI DevOps Tools Engineer @ Linux Academy

MSc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Técnico Lisboa - University of Lisbon | 2007 - 2013 [₱] Lisbon, Portugal

- Major / Minor: Robotics & Control Systems / Computers
- Principal subjects: Database management, Objects Oriented Programming, Robotics
- Thesis: Quadcopter/Drone Automatic Take Off / Landing on a (mobile) Docking Station

OTHER TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

2022 - Advent Of Code 2022 - 25 days live solving tech riddles with Go - aithub.com/tcarreira/aoc2022 Speaker @ Python Brasil (tsuru) - youtu.be/gyLS37NVQHw FOSDEM 2022: Ubuntu stand website design & support - stands.fosdem.org/stands/ubuntu

2021 - TreeTree2: computer architecture I - github.com/tcarreira/nand2tetris-autograder

2020 - Podcasting (host, audio editor, web developer, designer) - github.com/marmita-de-redon Dashboard website project using Golang - github.com/tcarreira/roaw2020

2019 - Speaker @ Meetups and Conferences (Docker, Python, Terraform...) - tcarreira.github.io/presentations Volunteer (technical) @ Ubucon Europe 2019 - github.com/ubuconeurope

2018 - TreeTree2: HAC - Hacking the learn process on math/physics/programming with 10-16yo people

PERSONAL ENDEAVORS

Sports: running (marathon), cycling (Lisbon-Santiago 600+ Km), obstacle course racing, rock climbing Music: clarinet, transverse flute, guitar, piano

Music groups: company's band, TUIST.tecnico.ulisboa.pt, multiple choirs, philharmonic orchestra Video production: youtube.carreira.pw, youtu.be/IKvtB-vNOek

Podcasting: marmita.pt (github.com/Marmita-de-Redon)

Personal skills: therapeutic massage (advanced integrated therapeutic massage course) Maker: Arduino, Raspberry Pi